Well then, I'm off.
Please be careful on your way, Haruto-san.
Stay safe!
Haruto-niichan, by the time you get back,
I'll be completely fluent in Strahlian!
Aishia, look after everyone for me.
Leave it to me.
Be careful.
Discharge.
Teleport.
He disappeared!
For real? Wow!
Spirit Chronicles 2
Aki-chan!
Here it comes!
Ai-chan...
What is that thing?
I think it's probably a monster.
My Home, Under Attack
The Village of the Spirits.
It seems I've returned safely.
Onii-chan!
Latifa!
Welcome home, Onii-chan!
Welcome home!
Thank you. Have you been well?
Yes! Yes!
You see? It really is Master Rio!
Master Rio, welcome home.
We felt a great distortion
in the magical energy nearby,
so we thought you might
have returned, Master Rio.
Latifa and Big Sis Sara came
rushing over here. It was chaos.
A-Alma, you seemed like you were
trying to pass us to get here!
Everyone wanted to see Onii-chan
as quickly as possible, right?
Huh?
Um...
Well...
I've actually come because I want to
consult the Elders about something.
I see. Then I'll inform
the Eldest immediately.
Then the rushing torrent of od and mana
that came here from the Strahl region
could have been the result of
those six pillars of light?
Yes, I believe so.
I think that the pillars of light
were a type of space-time magic.
What's more, I believe it was used to
summon people from outside of this world.
In the Strahl region,
there are rumors that the six Heroes
from the Divine-Demon War have appeared.
Heroes.
Yes.
Sir Rio, why do you think that the Heroes
were summoned from outside this world?
Because I have taken in two girls and
one boy who lived in that other world.
Then the three of them are Heroes?
No, I don't think they are.
They were in a place that wasn't
connected to the light pillars.
However, they were with two other people
until just before they were transported,
and they say they saw those
two taken by a rift in space.
Then the ones who were
summoned as Heroes were...
Yes, the other two.
I think the three I took in might have
been caught up in the summoning.
Sir Rio, you were able to communicate
with people from another world?
Yes, I was.
To be precise, I know their language.
How can that be possible?
In my previous life, I lived
in the same world as them.
Previous life?
I'll explain about that at a later time.
For the moment, I hope that
the explanation I've given
is enough to gain your understanding.
Very well.
We will set that matter aside for the moment.
You have my gratitude.
And this is difficult for me to ask,
but I have a request to make of you.
Sir Rio, if it is you making the request,
I would like to do whatever is possible.
The three I just mentioned,
and one more person...
would it be possible for me to leave them
here in the village for a short time?
Will you tell us more?
I would like to look for clues
as to how to return the three
I've taken in to their own world.
However, while they are under my protection,
it is difficult for me to take action.
And, in terms of knowledge
about space-time magic,
I can in no way compare to
the people of this village.
Magic which makes it possible
to cross between worlds...
We cannot even guess what that might be.
And that's why you want
to leave them with us?
Yes.
And who is the other?
A teacher to whom I owe much.
She was forced into a political
marriage against her will.
On the day of her wedding,
I rescued her from it.
I just couldn't bring myself
to overlook her plight.
That's well done, you lady-killer!
All right. We'll look after the
lot of them for you. Right?
Honestly, you always...
Well, I suppose I have no objections.
Neither do I.
However...
when those four eventually
return to the Strahl region,
I ask that they solemnly promise that
they will keep information
about our village a secret.
Of course. I will explain the
importance of it to them.
Then I will leave tomorrow
and bring them here
Latifa, were you able to
understand the discussion today?
Yes.
I spoke about my past life without
your permission. I'm sorry.
But if I hadn't done that, I wouldn't have
been able to explain things to the Eldest.
Do you think I should
tell them about myself, too?
You don't have to force yourself
to tell anyone, Latifa.
The people you were talking
about are Japanese, right?
Yes.
Does that mean that you told them you
used to be Japanese too, Onii-chan?
If I hadn't, they would have wondered
why I could understand their language.
But that was a secret
between just you and me.
Hey! Why are you smiling?
I guess it's because
you're being cute, Latifa.
No fair.
You don't play fair, Onii-chan.
Hey, Latifa?
Even if other people from
Japan besides us appear,
it doesn't change the fact
that you're special to me.
Right.
Do you remember what I told
you about my past life?
That I was in love with
my childhood friend,
or that I had a little sister who I lived
apart from after our parents divorced?
Yes.
One of the three people I took in...
is the person I loved all my life
when I was Amakawa Haruto.
Her name is Ayase Miharu.
What?
And one of the others, Sendo Aki-chan...
We only lived together for a little over
three years, but she was my little sister.
Little sister?
But I haven't told them that
I have Amakawa Haruto's memories.
Why not?
After suddenly finding
themselves in another world,
they must feel unsteady,
emotionally speaking.
And the person who I am now...
isn't Amakawa Haruto.
That's why I hope you won't tell them
about my past life either, Latifa.
Onii-chan, you actually want
to tell them, don't you?
No, I don't.
Onii-chan! Tell me how you really feel!
If you don't, then I can't
make that promise to you.
The person I was in my past life...
I guess I want to keep that
just our secret, Latifa.
I might have to tell
someone about it someday,
but not yet.
No fair.
You really don't play fair, Onii-chan.
Calling feelings like those a lie...
I just can't do it.
How long do you think it
will be before you return?
I think I'll be back in about two weeks.
I'll be back, Latifa.
Stay safe, Onii-chan.
She's still at an age when
she wants to be babied.
It'll be all right, Latifa.
Then I'll be going.
Come back safely!
Capital of the Kingdom of Beltrum, Beltrant
Those are the particulars of the events
in the Beltrum Kingdom's royal capital.
Thank you for your report.
You are too kind, King Francois.
It pains me to ask this when
you've only just returned,
King Francois Galarc
but I must make a request.
I would like you to call upon Duke Huguenot.
It would be my pleasure!
What should I do there?
I truest you are aware that the sacred stone in
our kingdom's possession has summoned a Hero.
Yes, I have heard she is a
girl around my age.
For that reason, we are inviting
ambassadors from neighboring kingdoms
and plan to hold a soirée
to present the Hero.
I see.
We would like to offer the Hero
summoned to the Beltrum Kingdom
a place at that occasion.
I would ask you to deliver
the invitation in my stead.
I humbly accept this responsibility.
I've heard that their Hero is a young man.
His name is Sakata Hiroaki.
Sir Sakata Hiroaki?
Yes, apparently it is the custom where he
is from to put one's family name first.
Sir Sakata Hiroaki?
Somehow it has a nostalgic sound to it.
Nostalgic? Does it really?
N-Not at all! I haven't really
heard a name like it before!
Sir Sakata Hiroaki.
Could it be?
Your Majesty,
may I ask the name of the Hero
who was summoned to our kingdom?
It's Dame Sumeragi Satsuki.
Given the way she says her family name first,
she may be from the same land as Sir Hiroaki.
The same land?
Sakata Hiroaki. Sumeragi Satsuki.
As I thought...
I thought it would be best for you to meet her,
so I've asked her to wait in another room.
Charlotte, show her the way.
Yes, Father.
Lady Satsuki? May we intrude?
Come in.
Pleased to meet you. Are you Miss Liselotte?
Spirit Chronicles 2
It's no wonder the Ricca Merchant Company
has their base of operations in this town.
It excels all around.
I've found myself some
very good blank figurines.
Now go.
Find anyone within the forest
on the outskirts of Amande
who is enveloped in a
large quantity of magic.
Bring them to me alive.
Kill as many unnecessary
witnesses as possible.
You have until sundown tomorrow.
With this, I should have as
many blank dolls as I require.
I suppose that means it's time.
I'll use this last opportunity to make
some money, then lay low for a while.
It's just about time for lunch.
I'm getting hungry.
U-Um...
Already? It's afternoon. Stomach?
Um... Um...
My stomach feels so empty.
Your stomach... hurts!
It's empty.
I actually knew that!
I knew that!
But you know, Masato...
you've improved a lot over these last two weeks.
Do you think Haruto-san will be back soon?
Miharu-oneechan, that's all you've
talked about since last night.
What? Have I?
How long will we be living like this?
Living like this?
We should be starting a new school term,
starting a new chapter in life, but instead...
And Onii-chan and Satsuki-san
disappeared, too.
And I may never see Mom
or anyone else I know again.
You're worried, aren't you?
Aren't you worried, Miharu-oneechan?
I might be worried, but you
and Masato-kun are here.
And there's Ai-chan,
Celia-san... and Haruto-san.
I suppose that makes me feel calmer somehow.
Miharu-oneechan, don't you want to go back?
I don't think that panicking
will help anything.
And Haruto-san is doing all
sorts of things for us.
Right now, all we can do is
leave things to Haruto-san.
Haruto-san.
Miharu-oneechan, what do
you think of Haruto-san?
What? What do you mean?
Miharu-oneechan, you're supposed
to be anxious around men...
but you act completely naturally around
Haruto-san. You seem like you're having fun.
I-I don't know about that.
We rely on him, and I do think
he's a very kind person.
Plus...
Plus what?
Maybe it's because he has the same
name as Haru-kun. Somehow he—
You're still thinking about that guy?
Aki-chan!
Comparing him to a guy like that...
is rude to Haruto-san!
I-I'm sorry. That wasn't my intention.
I'm sorry.
No, I should apologize.
I'm going to go cool off.
Aki-chan.
I'm such an idiot.
Miharu-oneechan hasn't done anything wrong.
I wonder if Miharu-oneechan still
loves that guy, Amakawa Haruto.
But...
Oh, I just don't know!
Aki-chan...
Miharu-oneechan.
Um, I...
Wh-What are those?
We have to hurry back inside!
Aki-chan!
Wh-What's that?
Something blew up, didn't it?
Masato, stay here.
What? What did you say?
Don't move! All right?
Ai-chan, what is that thing?
I think it's probably a monster.
It may have been drawn here by
the barrier's magical energy.
I-It's still alive?
Both of you, stand back.
Aishia, look after everyone for me.
I will protect Miharu and the others!
Aishia!
Leave these two to me!
I'm sorry I took so long.
Rio!
Haruto-san...
What was that resistance just now?
It's tough.
Aishia, do you know anything about them?
No, but they have the same feel as monsters.
Also, the darker one is probably stronger.
Then I'll draw that one to me.
Aishia, can I leave the two grey ones to you?
It's fast, but it moves in straight lines.
And its attack is just a big swing?
You're a tough one.
Does it understand me?
It's no good.
Its life force is so strong.
So it was a monster after all?
I defeated the other two.
Thank you.
Thank you, Professor.
Of course. Welcome back.
The way its mouth moved at the end...
It was just as if...
Please, kill me.
I'm really sorry!
It's all because I went outside!
No, it's my fault!
I said something insensitive
to Aki-chan and so she...
No! It's because I...
I'm sorry, Miharu-oneechan.
Please, we...
Something smells good.
What?
Oh, yes. We were in the
middle of preparing lunch.
Could it be omurice?
What? Um, yes.
I'm hungry! Let's have lunch!
I'm hungry, too!
Masato! Well done!
I'm starving, too.
Okay! It will be ready soon!
Aki-chan, will you help me?
Y-Yes.
Oh, right. Everyone?
We're going to be moving house.
One group hasn't returned.
Could their target have killed them?
Slaying a group of strengthened
revenants wouldn't be a simple thing.
It will delay my plans,
but the numbers have been reduced,
so I'd best make new
blank dolls immediately.
Now then...
I wonder how many will remain this time.
Next Time
Welcome Home
"Welcome Home."
Spirit Chronicles 2
Haruto!
Illustration: Minazuki Futago